<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on It&#39;s the Travis Amiel Blog</title>
    <link>https://travisamiel.github.io/blog/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on It&#39;s the Travis Amiel Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://travisamiel.github.io/blog/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s a Tuesday! This was my morning</title>
      <link>https://travisamiel.github.io/blog/posts/12may2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://travisamiel.github.io/blog/posts/12may2020/</guid>
      <description>How I start This morning — as most of my mornings in iso[lation] — started with checking my inboxes for anything that immediately needed to be handled.
I put away dishes and watered the saplings on the windowsill.
Then I meditated.
I made coffee and listened to the headlines from Democracy Now.
There was a little work to do for my job as a producer with HowlRound Theatre Commons.
Newsletters Next, I went through my morning newsletters including the Broadway Briefing and the spectaular Digestable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time to taste my kombucha and pickles</title>
      <link>https://travisamiel.github.io/blog/posts/fermentation-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://travisamiel.github.io/blog/posts/fermentation-1/</guid>
      <description>I am making kombucha. (a SCOBY from a neighbor + black tea)
I am making pickles. (cucumbers in a jar with salt)
After more than a week of letting each vessle do it&amp;rsquo;s thing, I moved the jar of kombucha into a bottle (for the second stage of brewing), and I ate a what can now be called a pickle.
The kombucha was flat and still too sweet. The pickle was mushy, and not quite bitter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why this live, why now</title>
      <link>https://travisamiel.github.io/blog/posts/why-this-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://travisamiel.github.io/blog/posts/why-this-live/</guid>
      <description>A quesiton that theatremakers people who put on plays often ask is &amp;ldquo;why this play, why now&amp;rdquo;.
Livestreaming (whether via a video call, or just to Facebook or YouTube) feels like the most analgous form for performers to work in while congregating isn&amp;rsquo;t possible, so when producing something consider: &amp;ldquo;why this live now&amp;rdquo;?
Will the audience gain something by being there as it is made? Will what is being made change because of the audience?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>