<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on It&#39;s the Travis Amiel Blog</title>
    <link>https://travisamiel.github.io/blog/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on It&#39;s the Travis Amiel Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://travisamiel.github.io/blog/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My Podcast Recommendations</title>
      <link>https://travisamiel.github.io/blog/posts/podcastrecommendations-v1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://travisamiel.github.io/blog/posts/podcastrecommendations-v1/</guid>
      <description>Preface I am of the conviction that podcasts are not in any way a new thing. I think of podcasts as a genre of distribution whereby an RSS feed serves up (usually) audio files. i.e. the producer offers a list/menu of files, along with information, and you are able to download the actual file—and the menu is in a standardized, agreed-upon format so reading the menu is clear to developers. This is mode of distribution is different than streaming video/audio online or tuning into a broadcast on radio/TV.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abundant archives of amazing performance</title>
      <link>https://travisamiel.github.io/blog/posts/abundantarchives/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://travisamiel.github.io/blog/posts/abundantarchives/</guid>
      <description>Missing You As I so deeply miss the uncomfortable, subversive, movement-driven, messy performances I came to NYC for, I have felt eccestatic by recordings which have popped up that I didn&amp;rsquo;t know existed. But the urgency to watch in a specific window, a limitation for the number of viewers, or cost have all felt like undue artificial restrictions.
Many have long offered robust, deep archives of their work—which I&amp;rsquo;d like to celebrate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Media Fasting</title>
      <link>https://travisamiel.github.io/blog/posts/22july2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://travisamiel.github.io/blog/posts/22july2020/</guid>
      <description>The Fast Feeling depressed recently, I&amp;rsquo;m markedly taking a social media fast—and even just like staying off all news during the day, but just for a smidgey. I&amp;rsquo;m still following my morning ritual of Digestable, Democracy Now, and the Broadway Briefing. I don&amp;rsquo;t like being off Twitter, since it is by scrolling I come across perspectives that shift my own.
For example this piece from Belgrade Theatre Coventry writing about why the organization will stop using umbrella terms for non-white people such as POC and BAME.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Since May</title>
      <link>https://travisamiel.github.io/blog/posts/09july2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://travisamiel.github.io/blog/posts/09july2020/</guid>
      <description>A lot of my time has been spent in video calls. This blog post titled &amp;lsquo;Power Dynamics and Inclusion in Virtual Meetings&amp;rsquo; reminds me of the multitudes of ways people come to technology. We all have different needs and understandings regarding the way our world, infrustructure, and platforms work.
Since the end of May, I&amp;rsquo;ve been retweeting-as-expression vis-à-vis abolition, systemic + institutional oppression, racism, transphobia, decolonization, sexual assult, and journaling about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tools to make</title>
      <link>https://travisamiel.github.io/blog/posts/26may2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://travisamiel.github.io/blog/posts/26may2020/</guid>
      <description>decoupling togetherness with real life
 I think I heard this as a quote somewhere, but I am not sure where.
While I&amp;rsquo;m reminding myself not to put any pressure of productivity on myself, I still enjoy making, expressing myself, experimenting, and playing as an activity. Rather than translating what I&amp;rsquo;d do in a theatre to a livestream, I&amp;rsquo;d like to talk about digital tools that build upon the skills I have as a performance artist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I dream this blog to be, v1</title>
      <link>https://travisamiel.github.io/blog/posts/blogdreams-v1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://travisamiel.github.io/blog/posts/blogdreams-v1/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes I wake in the middle of the night thinking I&amp;rsquo;ve figured out exactly how to make this blog perfect.
Right now I like that it&amp;rsquo;s built on Hugo and that it most importantly lives in little Markdown files that I own in a simple format and if I want to change the theme or host the blog somewhere else I can do that without any problems.
But then I come across a site like this https://wiki.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comforts, May 2020</title>
      <link>https://travisamiel.github.io/blog/posts/20may2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://travisamiel.github.io/blog/posts/20may2020/</guid>
      <description>Right now I&amp;rsquo;m listening to Surface Image by Tristan Perich and Vicky Chow.
Earlier today I had stuck in my head Philip Glass&amp;rsquo; &amp;lsquo;Dance VI&amp;rsquo; from In the Upper Room, and for a brief moment I just needed to hear Betty Buckley sing the final song from The Mystery of Edwin Drood.
Vibin Make a little orb farm via this online simulator is incredibly satisfying.
Thoeries Modern monetary theory: A different theoretical framework for considering economics is just so tasty right now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Work</title>
      <link>https://travisamiel.github.io/blog/posts/how-i-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://travisamiel.github.io/blog/posts/how-i-work/</guid>
      <description>I deeply love Lifehacker&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;How I Work&amp;rsquo; series, and wanted to write my own recap of the software &amp;amp; platforms I love.
My goal is to use as much open-source software, and after reading this series on Gizmodo, I&amp;rsquo;m wondering how I can utilize platforms that don&amp;rsquo;t have nefarious goals—I&amp;rsquo;m not perfect at all.
My essentials *Firefox for web browsing, and I search with Duck Duck Go.
Evernote is my extension of the brain, where everything is stored.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An update on the kombucha and pickles</title>
      <link>https://travisamiel.github.io/blog/posts/fermentation-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://travisamiel.github.io/blog/posts/fermentation-2/</guid>
      <description>First of all a big thank you to Jimmy for all of the hand-holding with this journey I have been on.
F2 I took the kombucha from my big vessel and ladled it with a funnel into an empty bottle I originally bought to refill with kombucha from a tap. The second fermentation (F2) is where carbination allegedly occurs.
In prep for another experiment, I froze blackberries—those will come back into the story later.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s a Tuesday! This was my morning</title>
      <link>https://travisamiel.github.io/blog/posts/12may2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://travisamiel.github.io/blog/posts/12may2020/</guid>
      <description>How I start This morning — as most of my mornings in iso[lation] — started with checking my inboxes for anything that immediately needed to be handled.
I put away dishes and watered the saplings on the windowsill.
Then I meditated.
I made coffee and listened to the headlines from Democracy Now.
There was a little work to do for my job as a producer with HowlRound Theatre Commons.
Newsletters Next, I went through my morning newsletters including the Broadway Briefing and the spectaular Digestable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time to taste my kombucha and pickles</title>
      <link>https://travisamiel.github.io/blog/posts/fermentation-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://travisamiel.github.io/blog/posts/fermentation-1/</guid>
      <description>I am making kombucha. (a SCOBY from a neighbor + black tea)
I am making pickles. (cucumbers in a jar with salt)
After more than a week of letting each vessle do it&amp;rsquo;s thing, I moved the jar of kombucha into a bottle (for the second stage of brewing), and I ate a what can now be called a pickle.
The kombucha was flat and still too sweet. The pickle was mushy, and not quite bitter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why this live, why now</title>
      <link>https://travisamiel.github.io/blog/posts/why-this-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://travisamiel.github.io/blog/posts/why-this-live/</guid>
      <description>A quesiton that theatremakers people who put on plays often ask is &amp;ldquo;why this play, why now&amp;rdquo;.
Livestreaming (whether via a video call, or just to Facebook or YouTube) feels like the most analgous form for performers to work in while congregating isn&amp;rsquo;t possible, so when producing something consider: &amp;ldquo;why this live now&amp;rdquo;?
Will the audience gain something by being there as it is made? Will what is being made change because of the audience?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>