<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>fermentation on It&#39;s the Travis Amiel Blog</title>
    <link>https://travisamiel.github.io/blog/tags/fermentation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in fermentation on It&#39;s the Travis Amiel Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://travisamiel.github.io/blog/tags/fermentation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Media Fasting</title>
      <link>https://travisamiel.github.io/blog/posts/22july2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://travisamiel.github.io/blog/posts/22july2020/</guid>
      <description>The Fast Feeling depressed recently, I&amp;rsquo;m markedly taking a social media fast—and even just like staying off all news during the day, but just for a smidgey. I&amp;rsquo;m still following my morning ritual of Digestable, Democracy Now, and the Broadway Briefing. I don&amp;rsquo;t like being off Twitter, since it is by scrolling I come across perspectives that shift my own.
For example this piece from Belgrade Theatre Coventry writing about why the organization will stop using umbrella terms for non-white people such as POC and BAME.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An update on the kombucha and pickles</title>
      <link>https://travisamiel.github.io/blog/posts/fermentation-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://travisamiel.github.io/blog/posts/fermentation-2/</guid>
      <description>First of all a big thank you to Jimmy for all of the hand-holding with this journey I have been on.
F2 I took the kombucha from my big vessel and ladled it with a funnel into an empty bottle I originally bought to refill with kombucha from a tap. The second fermentation (F2) is where carbination allegedly occurs.
In prep for another experiment, I froze blackberries—those will come back into the story later.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time to taste my kombucha and pickles</title>
      <link>https://travisamiel.github.io/blog/posts/fermentation-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://travisamiel.github.io/blog/posts/fermentation-1/</guid>
      <description>I am making kombucha. (a SCOBY from a neighbor + black tea)
I am making pickles. (cucumbers in a jar with salt)
After more than a week of letting each vessle do it&amp;rsquo;s thing, I moved the jar of kombucha into a bottle (for the second stage of brewing), and I ate a what can now be called a pickle.
The kombucha was flat and still too sweet. The pickle was mushy, and not quite bitter.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>